Guide to the Office of the Secretary, Yale University, Audio Recordings of Speeches, Assemblies, and Events
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Office of the Secretary, Yale University, audio recordings of speeches, assemblies, and events
1987-1993
RU 1108
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
(22 audiocassettes)
The materials consist of audio recordings of speeches, press conferences, assemblies, and other events coordinated by the Office of the Secretary.
Yale University. Office of the Secretary
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 4-C (YRG 4-C), Records documenting public information functions of Yale University.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were transferred from the Office of the Secretary, 1989-1995.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Biographical / Historical
The secretary is an administrative officer elected by the Yale Corporation on nomination of the president. The secretary prepares and keeps the records of the Corporation and in addition to being responsible for the safekeeping of the seal and other official University insignia, also supervises the election of alumni fellows to the Corporation, helps the president prepare all diplomas and certificates of award, and is responsible for the management of all official University functions and publications. The secretary works with a staff of associates which oversees such non-academic areas as the University Archives, the University Council, public information, university security, and community relations.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of audio recordings of speeches, press conferences, assemblies, and other events coordinated by the Office of the Secretary.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Lectures and lecturing; Speeches, addresses, etc.; Audiotapes; Yale University -- Commencement; Yale University -- Presidents -- Inaugurations; Yale University. Office of the Secretary
- Audio recordings, 1965, undated; Accession 19ND-A-501
  - Alumni forum, "Student Activities in the South" [part 1], 1965; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 1)
  - Alumni forum, "Student Activities in the South" [part 2], 1965; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 2)
  - David Ruffin interview, 1965; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 3)
  - Yale Reports (K.W. Deutsch, h.J. Benda, S. Hough, undated; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 4)
- Baccalaureate, class day, and commencement speeches [audiorecordings], 1987-1988; Accession 1989-A-002
  - Class day (part 1), 1987 May 24; audiocassette (Box 1)
    - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 1U)
  - Class day (part 2), 1987 May 24; audiocassette (Box 2)
    - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 2U)
  - Commencement, 1987 May 25; audiocassette (Box 3)
  - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 3U)
  - Commencement, 1988 May 30; audiocassette (Box 4)
    - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 4U)
  - Baccalaureate, 1988 May 29; audiocassette (Box 5)
  - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 5U)
  - Class day (part 1), 1988; audiocassette (Box 6)
  - Class day (part 2), 1988; audiocassette (Box 7)
- Addresses and press conferences [audiorecordings], 1988-1989; Accession 1990-A-036
  - Undergraduate assembly (Woolsey Hall), 1988 September 3; audiocassette (Box 1)
  - Graduate and professional assembly (Woolsey Hall), 1988 September 8; audiocassette (Box 2)
  - Freshman assembly, 1989 September 2; audiocassette (Box 3)
  - Yale tennis courts press conference, 1989 September 6; audiocassette (Box 4)
  - Graduate and professional assembly, 1989 September 7; audiocassette (Box 5)
- Freshman, Graduate, and Professional Assemblies [audiorecordings], 1990; Accession 1991-A-033
  - Freshman Assembly, Class of 1994 (Woolsey Hall), 1990 September 1; audiocassette (Box 1)
  - Graduate and Professional Assembly (Woolsey Hall), 1990 September 10; audiocassette (Box 2)
- Benno Schmidt inauguration, Howland Lecture, and press conferences, 1986-1993; Accession 1995-A-057
  - President Benno C. Schmidt, Jr. inauguration, 1986; audiocassette (Box 1)
    - Duplicating master, 1
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 1U)
  - Russel Baker, Howland lecture, 1990 March 27; audiocassette (Box 2)
    - Use copy, audiocassette (Box 2U)
  - Press conference (114SSS), 1993 June 24; audiocassette (Box 3)
  - Press conference (President's Room), 1993 June 25; audiocassette (Box 4)